Gate v2 verifies coding agent completion claims. This is a real task in a pinned clone of the iniconfig project, recorded from Codex Desktop.
I used Codex with GPT-5.6 to make the requested change. First, this is the ordinary workflow without Gate.
Codex starts on the same task, changes the real project, and runs its tests. The task may look complete, but only the agent's final message explains the result.
There is no protected task binding, independent verdict, or audit root. A developer must trust the claim, inspect the work manually, or try to reconstruct the evidence later.
That is the gap Gate addresses. Passing a narrow test or saying done is not the same as a completion claim that can be checked by someone else.
Now Gate is installed from the public master branch and discovered in Codex as gate at personal.
The gate run skill starts a fresh protected child task. The agent still performs the implementation work, while Gate enforces what has to be true before completion is accepted.
Gate binds the task, protects the verifier and test configuration, records the evidence, and independently checks the finished state.
Here, the child run changes the real project and runs the prescribed verification. Gate records manifest checks, timeout handling, the final claim, and the SHA-256 audit chain.
An agent cannot make a passing narrow test become a verified completion merely by writing a confident final message.
The result is FINAL VERIFIED. Gate reports the exact child thread ID, the audit root, and an independent verifier validates that chain.
Without Gate, Codex says the project is complete. With Gate, that completion claim is independently auditable.